{
    "instructions": "This multiple-choice quiz will determine which wordbook level is right for you. Each test word will be shown in BOLD CAPITAL letters in a phrase. From the five choices, select the one that comes closest in meaning to the meaning of the test word.",
    "type": "placement",
    "groups": [
      {
        "title": "Group One",
        "questions": [
          {
            "prompt": "She ESTABLISHED the business.",
            "answers": [
              "announced",
              "bought",
              "sold",
              "improved",
              "set up"
            ],
            "correct": "set up"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "Enjoying the EXPEDITION.",
            "answers": [
              "visit",
              "display",
              "journey",
              "boat race",
              "sights"
            ],
            "correct": "journey"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "Best way to INSTRUCT.",
            "answers": [
              "forget",
              "teach",
              "learn",
              "punish",
              "build"
            ],
            "correct": "teach"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "GNARLED branches.",
            "answers": [
              "old",
              "decorated",
              "smooth",
              "diseased",
              "twisted"
            ],
            "correct": "twisted"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "Tried to FLATTER him.",
            "answers": [
              "insult",
              "improve",
              "overpraise",
              "crush",
              "agree with"
            ],
            "correct": "overpraise"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "They were EXTERMINATED.",
            "answers": [
              "wiped out",
              "stopped",
              "beaten up",
              "cured",
              "thrown away"
            ],
            "correct": "wiped out"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "Began to LAG.",
            "answers": [
              "sink",
              "give up",
              "breathe heavily",
              "fall behind",
              "catch up"
            ],
            "correct": "fall behind"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "FATAL blows.",
            "answers": [
              "deadly",
              "soft",
              "natural",
              "first",
              "painful"
            ],
            "correct": "deadly"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "Powerful HEX.",
            "answers": [
              "evil",
              "prayer",
              "tool",
              "fear",
              "curse"
            ],
            "correct": "curse"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "Clever IMPOSTOR.",
            "answers": [
              "detective",
              "customer",
              "magician",
              "faker",
              "thief"
            ],
            "correct": "faker"
          }
        ]
      },
      {
        "title": "Group Two",
        "questions": [
          {
            "prompt": "Read the CONTRACT.",
            "answers": [
              "report",
              "instructions",
              "agreement",
              "decision",
              "statement"
            ],
            "correct": "agreement"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "Watched them SLITHER.",
            "answers": [
              "fall",
              "slide",
              "run",
              "jump",
              "fly"
            ],
            "correct": "slide"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "They were LEGISLATORS.",
            "answers": [
              "leaders",
              "teachers",
              "judges",
              "lawyers",
              "lawmakers"
            ],
            "correct": "lawmakers"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "Running PARALLEL.",
            "answers": [
              "side by side",
              "to a point",
              "across",
              "opposite",
              "at angles"
            ],
            "correct": "side by side"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "Completely LOGICAL.",
            "answers": [
              "reasonable",
              "wonderful",
              "serious",
              "true",
              "stupid"
            ],
            "correct": "reasonable"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "FIENDISH plans.",
            "answers": [
              "childish",
              "wonderful",
              "poor",
              "difficult",
              "devilish"
            ],
            "correct": "devilish"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "True MONARCH.",
            "answers": [
              "servant",
              "owner",
              "father",
              "ruler",
              "kingdom"
            ],
            "correct": "ruler"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "I can't RECOLLECT.",
            "answers": [
              "win",
              "remember",
              "say",
              "forget",
              "refuse"
            ],
            "correct": "remember"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "He SNICKERS.",
            "answers": [
              "groans",
              "sighs",
              "sneezes",
              "shouts",
              "laughs"
            ],
            "correct": "laughs"
          },
          {
             "prompt": "What is your VERDICT?",
             "answers": [
               "belief",
               "charge",
               "decision",
               "request",
               "excuse"
             ],
             "correct": "decision"
           }
         ]
      },
      {
        "title": "Group Three",
        "questions": [
          {
            "prompt": "It was REVOLTING.",
            "answers": [
              "foolish",
              "fascinating",
              "forbidden",
              "disgusting",
              "frightening"
            ],
            "correct": "disgusting"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "ENTRENCHED in their position.",
            "answers": [
              "fixed firmly",
              "lowered",
              "supported",
              "expected",
              "left"
            ],
            "correct": "fixed firmly"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "IDLE machines.",
            "answers": [
              "slow",
              "busy",
              "perfect",
              "poor",
              "unused"
            ],
            "correct": "unused"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "They ERECTED the statue.",
            "answers": [
              "moved",
              "tore down",
              "straightened",
              "raised up",
              "admired"
            ],
            "correct": "raised up"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "Wanted to EVALUATE it.",
            "answers": [
              "buy",
              "destroy",
              "rate",
              "improve",
              "sell"
            ],
            "correct": "rate"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "NEGLIGENT parents.",
            "answers": [
              "harsh",
              "helpful",
              "hardworking",
              "easygoing",
              "careless"
            ],
            "correct": "careless"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "SERENE attitude.",
            "answers": [
              "eager",
              "peaceful",
              "disgusting",
              "necessary",
              "hopeful"
            ],
            "correct": "peaceful"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "POTENTIAL candidates.",
            "answers": [
              "usual",
              "hopeless",
              "powerful",
              "possible",
              "young"
            ],
            "correct": "possible"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "They OBSTRUCTED the corridor.",
            "answers": [
              "built",
              "opened up",
              "blocked",
              "destroyed",
              "stood in"
            ],
            "correct": "blocked"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "RADIANT expressions.",
            "answers": [
              "sorrowful",
              "glowing",
              "unfriendly",
              "confident",
              "cheerful"
            ],
            "correct": "glowing"
          }
        ]
      },
      {
        "title": "Group Four",
        "questions": [
          {
            "prompt": "Knew the ARISTOCRACY.",
            "answers": [
              "church",
              "nobility",
              "magicians",
              "peasants",
              "businessman"
            ],
            "correct": "nobility"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "Strange LUSTER.",
            "answers": [
              "appearance",
              "shape",
              "smoothness",
              "warmth",
              "brightness"
            ],
            "correct": "brightness"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "Who will SUPERINTEND them?",
            "answers": [
              "manage",
              "protect",
              "expect",
              "obey",
              "improve"
            ],
            "correct": "manage"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "Great ZEAL.",
            "answers": [
              "pity",
              "confidence",
              "eagerness",
              "importance",
              "hope"
            ],
            "correct": "eagerness"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "SHIRK responsibility.",
            "answers": [
              "seek",
              "laugh at",
              "avoid",
              "lose",
              "hate"
            ],
            "correct": "avoid"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "Unusual COMPASSION.",
            "answers": [
              "game",
              "payment",
              "pity",
              "sickness",
              "pride"
            ],
            "correct": "pity"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "Inclined to RAMBLE.",
            "answers": [
              "return",
              "shake",
              "fall",
              "rush",
              "wander"
            ],
            "correct": "wander"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "Surprised by the STENCH.",
            "answers": [
              "mess",
              "stink",
              "dust",
              "noise",
              "heat"
            ],
            "correct": "stink"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "Great REMORSE.",
            "answers": [
              "ability",
              "pleasure",
              "hatred",
              "regret",
              "anger"
            ],
            "correct": "regret"
          },
          {
            "prompt": " New FORMAT.",
            "answers": [
              "covering",
              "arrangement",
              "contents",
              "idea",
              "requirements"
            ],
            "correct": "arrangement"
           }
         ]
      },
      {
        "title": "Group Five",
        "questions": [
          {
            "prompt": "DICTATORIAL manner.",
            "answers": [
              "meek",
              "convincing",
              "royal",
              "overbearing",
              "businesslike"
            ],
            "correct": "overbearing"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "We RELISH it.",
            "answers": [
              "dislike",
              "need",
              "study",
              "approve of",
              "enjoy"
            ],
            "correct": "enjoy"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "DON the coat.",
            "answers": [
              "put on",
              "finish",
              "brush",
              "take off",
              "choose"
            ],
            "correct": "put on"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "Typical LIVELIHOOD.",
            "answers": [
              "fast dance",
              "hobby",
              "criminal",
              "investment",
              "means of support"
            ],
            "correct": "means of support"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "To ASSERT that it is true.",
            "answers": [
              "believe",
              "pretend",
              "hope",
              "declare",
              "deny"
            ],
            "correct": "declare"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "INVOKE his mercy.",
            "answers": [
              "hope for",
              "expect",
              "call upon",
              "accept",
              "refuse"
            ],
            "correct": "call upon"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "Discussed its UTILITY.",
            "answers": [
              "power",
              "usefulness",
              "importance",
              "result",
              "uselessness"
            ],
            "correct": "usefulness"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "They PARTITIONED the area.",
            "answers": [
              "divided",
              "sought",
              "destroyed",
              "united",
              "surrounded"
            ],
            "correct": "divided"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "GROPE for them.",
            "answers": [
              "go out",
              "wish",
              "ask angrily",
              "feel blindly",
              "wait"
            ],
            "correct": "feel blindly"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "A common FALLACY.",
            "answers": [
              "false idea",
              "understanding",
              "lie",
              "old saying",
              "truth"
            ],
            "correct": "false idea"
          }
        ]
      },
      {
        "title": "Group Six",
        "questions": [
          {
            "prompt": "Remarkable AFFINITY.",
            "answers": [
              "concern",
              "distrust",
              "attraction",
              "history",
              "distance"
            ],
            "correct": "attraction"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "Amazing VISTA.",
            "answers": [
              "area",
              "future",
              "view",
              "times",
              "idea"
            ],
            "correct": "view"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "ASPIRE to be the leader.",
            "answers": [
              "demand",
              "ask",
              "long",
              "claim",
              "refuse"
            ],
            "correct": "long"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "Completely ASSIMILATED.",
            "answers": [
              "rejected",
              "hidden",
              "absorbed",
              "recognized",
              "revealed"
            ],
            "correct": "absorbed"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "The IMPETUS behind it.",
            "answers": [
              "rushing around",
              "happiness",
              "thought",
              "moving force",
              "indifference"
            ],
            "correct": "moving force"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "ARDENT desire.",
            "answers": [
              "new",
              "real",
              "constant",
              "burning",
              "mild"
            ],
            "correct": "burning"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "He will CONFOUND you.",
            "answers": [
              "anger",
              "please",
              "discover",
              "impress",
              "confuse"
            ],
            "correct": "confuse"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "REVEL until dawn.",
            "answers": [
              "sleep",
              "make merry",
              "fight",
              "sing",
              "work hard"
            ],
            "correct": "make merry"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "BESTIAL behavior.",
            "answers": [
              "criminal",
              "excellent",
              "animal-like",
              "logical",
              "unusual"
            ],
            "correct": "animal-like"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "Forget about the ORDEAL.",
            "answers": [
              "triumph",
              "contract",
              "accident",
              "severe trial",
              "strange sight"
            ],
            "correct": "severe trial"
          }
        ]
      },
      {
        "title": "Group Seven",
        "questions": [
          {
            "prompt": "Why did they VILIFY him?",
            "answers": [
              "slander",
              "appease",
              "despise",
              "terrify",
              "cheat"
            ],
            "correct": "slander"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "ABNEGATION is a way of life.",
            "answers": [
              "improvement",
              "cancellation",
              "self-denial",
              "indulgence",
              "purity"
            ],
            "correct": "self-denial"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "AMENABLE people.",
            "answers": [
              "happy",
              "submissive",
              "irresponsible",
              "holy",
              "fragile"
            ],
            "correct": "submissive"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "ASCETIC habits.",
            "answers": [
              "holy",
              "self-indulgent",
              "beautiful",
              "austere",
              "powerful"
            ],
            "correct": "austere"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "BELLICOSE manner.",
            "answers": [
              "warlike",
              "peaceful",
              "comical",
              "overweight",
              "evil"
            ],
            "correct": "warlike"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "She was BENIGN.",
            "answers": [
              "kindly",
              "lovely",
              "silent",
              "malicious",
              "unforgiving"
            ],
            "correct": "kindly"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "They were CREDULOUS.",
            "answers": [
              "stupid",
              "unknown",
              "extravagant",
              "suspicious",
              "gullible"
            ],
            "correct": "gullible"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "The PARADIGM was discussed.",
            "answers": [
              "story",
              "model",
              "lesson",
              "copy",
              "result"
            ],
            "correct": "model"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "SEQUESTER the animal.",
            "answers": [
              "isolate",
              "assemble",
              "harass",
              "protect",
              "follow"
            ],
            "correct": "isolate"
          },
          {
            "prompt": "A STODGY person.",
            "answers": [
              "lively",
              "old",
              "cruel",
              "dull",
              "clever"
            ],
            "correct": "dull"
          }
        ]
      },
      {
        "title": "Group Eight",
        "questions": [
          {
            "prompt": "EQUABLE behavior.",
            "answers": [
              "irascible",
              "fair-minded",
              "pliable",
              "even-tempered",
              "rational"
          ],
          "correct": "even-tempered"
        },
          {
            "prompt": "APOCRYPHAL story.",
            "answers": [
              "mysterious",
              "ancient",
              "spurious",
              "inspired",
              "deceitful"
          ],
          "correct": "spurious"
        },
          {
            "prompt": "Her REFULGENT smile.",
            "answers": [
              "disgusting",
              "gleaming",
              "swelling",
              "echoing",
              "exciting"
          ],
          "correct": "gleaming"
        },
          {
            "prompt": "MERETRICIOUS appearance.",
            "answers": [
              "exemplary",
              "elegant",
              "tawdry",
              "auspicious",
              "fiendish"
          ],
          "correct": "tawdry"
        },
          {
            "prompt": "Muttering an IMPRECATION.",
            "answers": [
              "praise",
              "involvement",
              "curse",
              "accusation",
              "shout"
          ],
          "correct": "curse"
        },
          {
            "prompt": "To VITIATE.",
            "answers": [
              "spoil",
              "cleanse",
              "soften",
              "remove",
              "transform"
          ],
          "correct": "spoil"
        },
          {
            "prompt": "PROTEAN force.",
            "answers": [
              "powerful",
              "invisible",
              "nautical",
              "growing",
              "changeable"
          ],
          "correct": "changeable"
        },
          {
            "prompt": "A PERSPICUOUS meaning.",
            "answers": [
              "hidden",
              "difficult",
              "uncommon",
              "famous",
              "clear"
          ],
          "correct": "clear"
        },
          {
            "prompt": "To OBVIATE the problem.",
            "answers": [
              "conceal",
              "reveal",
              "change",
              "prevent",
              "reduce"
          ],
          "correct": "prevent"
        },
          {
            "prompt": "FULSOME speech.",
            "answers": [
              "pleasant",
              "sickening",
              "flowery",
              "important",
              "deceitful"
            ],
            "correct": "sickening"
          }
        ]
      }
    ]
}
